{"title": "Hadoop", "questions": [{"question": "Q1. Partitioner controls the partitioning of what data?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " final keys\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " final values\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " intermediate keys\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " intermediate values\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q2. SQL Windowing functions are implemented in Hive using which keywords?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " UNION DISTINCT, RANK\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " OVER, RANK\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " OVER, EXCEPT\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " UNION DISTINCT, RANK\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q3. Rather than adding a Secondary Sort to a slow Reduce job, it is Hadoop best practice to perform which optimization?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Add a partitioned shuffle to the Map job.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Add a partitioned shuffle to the Reduce job.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Break the Reduce job into multiple, chained Reduce jobs.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Break the Reduce job into multiple, chained Map jobs.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q4. Hadoop Auth enforces authentication on protected resources. Once authentication has been established, it sets what type of authenticating cookie?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " encrypted HTTP\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " unsigned HTTP\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " compressed HTTP\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " signed HTTP\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q5. MapReduce jobs can be written in which language?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Java or Python\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " SQL only\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " SQL or Java\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Python or SQL\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q6. To perform local aggregation of the intermediate outputs, MapReduce users can optionally specify which object?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Reducer\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Combiner\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Mapper\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Counter\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q7. To verify job status, look for the value <code>___</code> in the <code>___</code>.\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " SUCCEEDED; syslog\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " SUCCEEDED; stdout\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " DONE; syslog\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DONE; stdout\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q8. Which line of code implements a Reducer method in MapReduce 2.0?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " public void reduce(Text key, Iterator<IntWritable> values, Context context){\u2026}\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " public static void reduce(Text key, IntWritable[] values, Context context){\u2026}\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " public static void reduce(Text key, Iterator<IntWritable> values, Context context){\u2026}\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " public void reduce(Text key, IntWritable[] values, Context context){\u2026}\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q9. To get the total number of mapped input records in a map job task, you should review the value of which counter?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " FileInputFormatCounter\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " FileSystemCounter\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " JobCounter\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " TaskCounter (NOT SURE)\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q10. Hadoop Core supports which CAP capabilities?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " A, P\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " C, A\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " C, P\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " C, A, P\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q11. What are the primary phases of a Reducer?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " combine, map, and reduce\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " shuffle, sort, and reduce\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " reduce, sort, and combine\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " map, sort, and combine\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q12. To set up Hadoop workflow with synchronization of data between jobs that process tasks both on disk and in memory, use the <code>___</code> service, which is <code>___</code>.\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Oozie; open source\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Oozie; commercial software\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Zookeeper; commercial software\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Zookeeper; open source\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q13. For high availability, use multiple nodes of which type?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " data\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " name\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " memory\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " worker\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q14. DataNode supports which type of drives?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " hot swappable\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " cold swappable\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " warm swappable\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " non-swappable\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q15. Which method is used to implement Spark jobs?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " on disk of all workers\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " on disk of the master node\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " in memory of the master node\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " in memory of all workers\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q16. In a MapReduce job, where does the map() function run?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " on the reducer nodes of the cluster\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " on the data nodes of the cluster (NOT SURE)\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " on the master node of the cluster\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " on every node of the cluster\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q17. To reference a master file for lookups during Mapping, what type of cache should be used?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " distributed cache\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " local cache\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " partitioned cache\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " cluster cache\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q18. Skip bad records provides an option where a certain set of bad input records can be skipped when processing what type of data?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " cache inputs\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " reducer inputs\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " intermediate values\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " map inputs\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q19. Which command imports data to Hadoop from a MySQL database?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " spark import --connect jdbc:mysql://mysql.example.com/spark --username spark --warehouse-dir user/hue/oozie/deployments/spark\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " sqoop import --connect jdbc:mysql://mysql.example.com/sqoop --username sqoop --warehouse-dir user/hue/oozie/deployments/sqoop\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " sqoop import --connect jdbc:mysql://mysql.example.com/sqoop --username sqoop --password sqoop --warehouse-dir user/hue/oozie/deployments/sqoop\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " spark import --connect jdbc:mysql://mysql.example.com/spark --username spark --password spark --warehouse-dir user/hue/oozie/deployments/spark\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q20. In what form is Reducer output presented?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " compressed (NOT SURE)\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " sorted\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " not sorted\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " encrypted\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q21. Which library should be used to unit test MapReduce code?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " JUnit\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " XUnit\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " MRUnit\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " HadoopUnit\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q22. If you started the NameNode, then which kind of user must you be?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " hadoop-user\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " super-user\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " node-user\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " admin-user\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q23. State _ between the JVMs in a MapReduce job\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " can be configured to be shared\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " is partially shared\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " is shared\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " is not shared (https://www.lynda.com/Hadoop-tutorials/Understanding-Java-virtual-machines-JVMs/191942/369545-4.html)\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q24. To create a MapReduce job, what should be coded first?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " a static job() method\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a Job class and instance (NOT SURE)\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " a job() method\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a static Job class\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q25. To connect Hadoop to AWS S3, which client should you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " S3A\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " S3N\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " S3\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " the EMR S3\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q26. HBase works with which type of schema enforcement?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " schema on write\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " no schema\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " external schema\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " schema on read\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q27. HDFS file are of what type?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " read-write\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " read-only\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " write-only\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " append-only\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q28. A distributed cache file path can originate from what location?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " hdfs or top\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " http\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " hdfs or http\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " hdfs\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q29. Which library should you use to perform ETL-type MapReduce jobs?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Hive\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Pig\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Impala\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Mahout\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q30. What is the output of the Reducer?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " a relational table\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " an update to the input file\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a single, combined list\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a set of <key, value> pairs\n</ul>\n<p><code>map function processes a certain key-value pair and emits a certain number of key-value pairs and the Reduce function processes values grouped by the same key and emits another set of key-value pairs as output.</code></p>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q31. To optimize a Mapper, what should you perform first?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Override the default Partitioner.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Skip bad records.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Break up Mappers that do more than one task into multiple Mappers.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Combine Mappers that do one task into large Mappers.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q32. When implemented on a public cloud, with what does Hadoop processing interact?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " files in object storage\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " graph data in graph databases\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " relational data in managed RDBMS systems\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " JSON data in NoSQL databases\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q33. In the Hadoop system, what administrative mode is used for maintenance?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " data mode\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " safe mode\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " single-user mode\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " pseudo-distributed mode\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q34. In what format does RecordWriter write an output file?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " <key, value> pairs\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " keys\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " values\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " <value, key> pairs\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q35. To what does the Mapper map input key/value pairs?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " an average of keys for values\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a sum of keys for values\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a set of intermediate key/value pairs\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " a set of final key/value pairs\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q36. Which Hive query returns the first 1,000 values?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " SELECT\u2026WHERE value = 1000\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " SELECT \u2026 LIMIT 1000\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " SELECT TOP 1000 \u2026\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " SELECT MAX 1000\u2026\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q37. To implement high availability, how many instances of the master node should you configure?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " one\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " zero\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " shared\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " two or more (https://data-flair.training/blogs/hadoop-high-availability-tutorial)\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q38. Hadoop 2.x and later implement which service as the resource coordinator?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " kubernetes\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " JobManager\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " JobTracker\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " YARN\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q39. In MapReduce, <strong>_</strong> have _\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " tasks; jobs\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " jobs; activities\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " jobs; tasks\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " activities; tasks\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q40. What type of software is Hadoop Common?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " database\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " distributed computing framework\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " operating system\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " productivity tool\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q41. If no reduction is desired, you should set the numbers of _ tasks to zero\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " combiner\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " reduce\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " mapper\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " intermediate\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q42. MapReduce applications use which of these classes to report their statistics?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " mapper\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " reducer\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " combiner\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " counter\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q43. _ is the query language, and _ is storage for NoSQL on Hadoop\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " HDFS; HQL\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " HQL; HBase\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " HDFS; SQL\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " SQL; HBase\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q44. MapReduce 1.0 _ YARN\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " does not include\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " is the same thing as\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " includes\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " replaces\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q45. Which type of Hadoop node executes file system namespace operations like opening, closing, and renaming files and directories?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " ControllerNode\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DataNode\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " MetadataNode\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " NameNode\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q46. HQL queries produce which job types?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Impala\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " MapReduce\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Spark\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Pig\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q47. Suppose you are trying to finish a Pig script that converts text in the input string to uppercase. What code is needed on line 2 below?\n<p>1 data = LOAD '/user/hue/pig/examples/data/midsummer.txt'...\n2</p>\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " as (text:CHAR[]); upper_case = FOREACH data GENERATE org.apache.pig.piggybank.evaluation.string.UPPER(TEXT);\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " as (text:CHARARRAY); upper_case = FOREACH data GENERATE org.apache.pig.piggybank.evaluation.string.UPPER(TEXT);\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " as (text:CHAR[]); upper_case = FOREACH data org.apache.pig.piggybank.evaluation.string.UPPER(TEXT);\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " as (text:CHARARRAY); upper_case = FOREACH data org.apache.pig.piggybank.evaluation.string.UPPER(TEXT);\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q48. In a MapReduce job, which phase runs after the Map phase completes?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Combiner\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Reducer\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Map2\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Shuffle and Sort\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q49. Where would you configure the size of a block in a Hadoop environment?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " dfs.block.size in hdfs-site.xmls\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " orc.write.variable.length.blocks in hive-default.xml\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " mapreduce.job.ubertask.maxbytes in mapred-site.xml\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " hdfs.block.size in hdfs-site.xml\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q50. Hadoop systems are <strong>_</strong> RDBMS systems.\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " replacements for\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " not used with\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " substitutes for\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " additions for\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q51. Which object can be used to distribute jars or libraries for use in MapReduce tasks?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " distributed cache\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " library manager\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " lookup store\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " registry\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q52. To view the execution details of an Impala query plan, which function would you use ?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " explain\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " query action\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " detail\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " query plan\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q53. Which feature is used to roll back a corrupted HDFS instance to a previously known good point in time?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " partitioning\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " snapshot\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " replication\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " high availability\n</ul>\n<p><a href=\"https://hadoop.apache.org/docs/r1.2.1/hdfs_design.html#:~:text=is%20not%20supported.-,Snapshots,known%20good%20point%20in%20time.\">Reference</a></p>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q54. Hadoop Common is written in which language?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " C++\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " C\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Haskell\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Java\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q55. Which file system does Hadoop use for storage?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " NAS\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " FAT\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " HDFS\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " NFS\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q56. What kind of storage and processing does Hadoop support?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " encrypted\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " verified\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " distributed\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " remote\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q57. Hadoop Common consists of which components?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Spark and YARN\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " HDFS and MapReduce\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " HDFS and S3\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Spark and MapReduce\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q58. Most Apache Hadoop committers' work is done at which commercial company?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Cloudera\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Microsoft\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Google\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Amazon\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q59. To get information about Reducer job runs, which object should be added?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Reporter\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " IntReadable\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " IntWritable\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Writer\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q60. After changing the default block size and restarting the cluster, to which data does the new size apply?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " all data\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " no data\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " existing data\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " new data\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q61. Which statement should you add to improve the performance of the following query?\n<p><code>sql\nSELECT\n  c.id,\n  c.name,\n  c.email_preferences.categories.surveys\nFROM customers c;</code></p>\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " GROUP BY\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " FILTER\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " SUB-SELECT\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " SORT\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q62. What custom object should you implement to reduce IO in MapReduce?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Comparator\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Mapper\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Combiner\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Reducer\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q63. You can optimize Hive queries using which method?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " secondary indices\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " summary statistics\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " column-based statistics\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a primary key index\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q64. If you are processing a single action on each input, what type of job should you create?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " partition-only\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " map-only\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " reduce-only\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " combine-only\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q65. The simplest possible MapReduce job optimization is to perform which of these actions?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Add more master nodes.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Implement optimized InputSplits.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Add more DataNodes.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Implement a custom Mapper.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q66. When you implement a custom Writable, you must also define which of these object?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " a sort policy\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a combiner policy\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a compression policy\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a filter policy\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q67. To copy a file into the Hadoop file system, what command should you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " hadoop fs -copy <fromDir> <toDir>\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " hadoop fs -copy <toDir> <fromDir>\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " hadoop fs -copyFromLocal <fromDir> <toDir>\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " hadoop fs -copyFromLocal <toDir> <fromDir>\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q68. Delete a Hive <strong>_</strong> table and you will delete the table <strong>_</strong>.\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " managed; metadata\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " external; data and metadata\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " external; metadata\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " managed; data\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q69. To see how Hive executed a JOIN operation, use the _ statement and look for the _ value.\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " EXPLAIN; JOIN Operator\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " QUERY; MAP JOIN Operator\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " EXPLAIN; MAP JOIN Operator\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " QUERY; JOIN Operator\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q70. Pig operates in mainly how many nodes?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Two\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Three\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Four\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Five\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q71. After loading data, <strong>_</strong> and then run a(n) <strong>_</strong> query for interactive queries.\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " invalidate metadata; Impala\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " validate metadata; Impala\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " invalidate metadata; Hive\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " validate metadata; Hive\n</ul>", "is_correct": false}]}]}